Preliminary Inventory to the Walker Downer Hines Papers, 1919-1927
Hoover Institution Archives
Walker Downer Hines Papers,
1919-1927
XX236
Walker D. Hines, 1870-1934
19 manuscript boxes ( linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Correspondence, memoranda, and reports, relating to questions of navigation rights on the Rhine, Danube, Elbe, Oder, and Vistula Rivers, restitution of captured ships, and reparations for war damage to river shipping, after World War I.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Access Points
International law.; International navigation--Laws and regulations.; International rivers.; Shipping.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--Reparations.
Container List
- Rhine River, June-October 1920 (Box 1, File 1)
- Documents on Hines' appointment to office (File 1A)
- Rhine River, October-November 22, 1920 (File 2)
- Rhine River, November 22-December 1, 1920 (File 3)
- Rhine River, December 1, 1920 - January 31, 1921 (Box 2, File 4)
- Rhine River, February 1, 1921 - March 4, 1921 (File 5)
- Documents on Hines' appointment to office (and German objections to) (File I-A-1)
- Official and original copies of armistices and conventions (File 8B)
- Hines' communications pertaining to Peace Conference relating to his office (File 8C)
- Nieman River file (includes a number of city street maps, reports, correspondence, postcard collection depicting river scenes) (File 12)
- Communications regarding delegations received by Hines (File 13)
- Danube - general (Box 3, File 19)
- Danube - Vienna Conferences, 1920-21 (File 19A)
- Danube - Sud-Deutsch vs. Czechoslovakia Case (File 19B)
- Correspondence with the European Danube Commission (File 19C)
- Correspondence with the Inter-Allied Commission on the Danube (File 19D)
- Correspondence regarding Roumania (File 19F)
- Roumanian accounting of Riparian materials captured from Central Powers (File 19F-1)
- Yugoslav accounting of river boats captured from Central Powers (File 19G-1)
- Danube - Czechoslovskian correspondence (File 19H)
- Danube - Hungary (Box 4, File 19M)
- Danube - Bulgaria (includes cross-reference of national claims and discrepancies in claims) (File 19N)
- Danube - France (File 19O)
- Danube - Great Britain (ownership) (File 19P)
- Danube - War Prize claims and allegations (File 19R)
- Danube - Germany (with reference to file 19P on Great Britain ownership) (File 19K)
- Danube - accounting and location of boats (File 19S-1)
- Lists of vessels delivered to Yugoslavia (File 19S-2)
- Danube - Restitutions (communications pertaining to (Box 5, File 19V)
- Danube - repatriation of passenger boats (File 19V-3)
- Danube - statistical predicates for resolving claims (File 19V-4)
- Danube - "Regularization" of the Danube (File 19V-5)
- Danube - sunken boats (File 19-Annex V)
- Danube - ammendments and additions to settlements (File 19-Annex IV)
- Accounts and audits of the Arbitrators Office (Box 6, File 21)
- Danube - additions and amendments to arbitrated questions (File 19-Annex IX)
- Danube - pontoons (File 19-Annex X)
- Elbe River, June 1920 - September 1921 (File 22)
- Elbe River, March 1921 - April 1922 (File 22)
- Elbe River - selection of boats reparation (File 22A)
- Elbe River - calculations and statistical predicates for deriving same (File 22B)
- Elbe River - reparation deliveries of Riparian equipment (File 22E)
- Oder River - general (Box 7, File 23)
- Oder River - calculations and statistical predicates (File 23B)
- Oder River - delivery of Riparian reparations (File 23C)
- Reparations Commission (Paris) correspondence (Box 8, File 32)
- Reparations Commission (Paris) on the German Riparian Fleet (File 32E)
- Reparations - miscellaneous committee meeting minutes (File 32F)
- Reparations - approval by recipients of installments (File 32G)
- Reparations - new construction agreements (File 32H)
- Reparations - objections to installments (re: 32G) (File 32J)
- Reparations - deliveries (File 32K)
- Rhine River - general (File 34)
- Rhine River - reparation claims of Dutch bankers (Box 9, File 34B)
- Rhine River - Rotterdam-Standard Oil reparation claims (File 34D)
- Rhine River - statistical predicates (File 34N)
- Rhine River - Karl Schraeders' boats, reparations (File 34P)
- Rhine River - selection of boats for reparation (File 34R)
- Rhine River - reparation deliveries (File 34X)
- Vistula River - general (Polish reparation claims) (File 39)
- Maps (File 43)
- Vistula River - Polish claims (Box 10, File 47)
- Elbe River - reparation decision (File 48)
- Oder River - reparation decision (File 49)
- Versailles Treaty - modifications to the conditions of cession (File 50)
- Danube River - reparation decision (File 51)
- Danube River - correspondence regarding the decision (file 51) with reference to file 19V-5 for further information (File 51)
- Rhine River - reparation decision (File 52)
- EMPTY (Box 11, File 53)
- Transfers of boat titles (File 57)
- Bank vouchers; miscellaneous regarding operations of Hines' office (File 54-55)
- Hines' office accounts and audit correspondence (Box 12)
- Hines' office accounts and correspondence pertaining to cost of running the office (Box 13)
- Miscellaneous documents
- Miscellaneous correspondence of Hines and the Commission (after Hines left it) (Box 14-15)
- Miscellaneous documents pertaining to Hines while arbitrator
- J. A. Logan, Jr., papers; intelligence on reparations; German economy, 1920 (Box 16)
- M. C. Bryant folder with reparation plan
- Miscellaneous reparation documents